[Road to Success]
[찬여번성: 별처럼 빛나리]
[Episode 17]
[제17화]
Good evening, Wang Fa.
안녕하세요, 왕파
I have seldom
전에
recorded this kind of stuff before.
이런 걸 별로 안 찍어 봐서
So I feel a bit shy.
좀 민망하네요
First of all,
먼저
thank you so much for your company recently
그동안 함께해 줘서 참 고마워요
[No.08, Ziwei Road]
[쯔웨이로 08]
and for coaching the players.
선수들을 잘 지도해 준 것도 정말 고맙고요
To you, these players
우리 선수들이 당신한테는
might just be passing strangers.
잠시 스쳐 가는 인연일지 몰라도
You helped them like casually rescuing drowning cats,
당신은 물에 빠진 고양이를 선뜻 구해 주듯
picking them up and letting them dry in the sun.
건져 올려 따뜻한 햇볕을 쬐게 해 줬죠
Wang Fa.
왕파
But you know what?
그거 알아요?
For a kitten,
고양이에게는
being bathed in the sunlight
햇볕을 쬘 수 있다는 게
is the happiest
살면서 가장 행복하고
and safest thing in its life.
안심이 되는 일이에요
Thank you so much.
정말 고마워요
Thank you.
감사합니다
Wanxing Lin.
완싱 린?
[Wanxing Lin's E-mail]
[완싱 린의 메일함]
Who registered this email?
누가 만든 이메일이지?
[Support all business and personal email accounts]
[기업 및 개인 이메일 지원]
[Verifying]
[확인 중]
[Yongchuan Hengjiu Football Club]
[융촨 헝주 축구 클럽]
[President's Office of Yongchuan Hengjiu Football Club]
[융촨 헝주 축구 클럽 회장실]
[Letter of Appointment from the Bureau]
[이사회 임명 통지서]
[Notice Regarding the Appointment of the New Head Coach]
[신임 감독 취임 안내]
Coach Liu Chuanguang is appointed
류촨광 코치
as the head coach of Yongchuan Hengjiu Club.
융촨 헝주 클럽 감독으로 취임
[Notice Regarding the Appointment of the New Head Coach]
[신임 감독 취임 안내]
Wang Fa isn't
융촨 헝주의 새 감독은
the new coach of Yongchuan Hengjiu?
왕파가 아니었어
♪ Night slips through my fingers ♪
♪ 밤은 손가락 틈새로 흘러 ♪
♪ Embracing the coldness of wakefulness ♪
♪ 깨어 있는 차가움을 감싸고 ♪
♪ Whispering my thoughts alone ♪
♪ 홀로 마음을 속삭이며 ♪
♪ Saying goodbye to the evening breeze I chanced upon ♪
♪ 우연히 마주친 밤바람과 작별하네 ♪
[School Area]
[학교 구역]
♪ Staying with the jasmine blossoms until late spring ♪
♪ 늦봄이 올 때까지 재스민 곁을 지키니 ♪
♪ Watching their elegance fade, their fragrance disappear ♪
♪ 우아하게 바래 가는 싱그러운 향기 ♪
♪ I once dreamed of something beautiful ♪
♪ 아름다운 것들과 꿈을 꾸었기에 ♪
♪ And I accept that regrets may grow wild ♪
♪ 아쉬움이 피어나는 것도 받아들이네 ♪
♪ Sharing my warmth with a passing rain ♪
♪ 한바탕 비와 체온을 나누네 ♪
♪ Quietly feeling its journey ♪
♪ 가만히 그 여정을 느껴 봐 ♪
Stop.
좀 세워 주세요
♪ Like a firefly vanishing in an instant ♪
♪ 반딧불처럼 순식간에 사라져 ♪
♪ Still beautiful in its entirety ♪
♪ 그래도 아름다움은 그대로야 ♪
♪ There's no need to seek a final answer ♪
♪ 굳이 결론을 내릴 필요는 없어 ♪
♪ Let the ending remain with questions unanswered ♪
♪ 끝에 의문이 남아도 괜찮아 ♪
♪ No need to prove it with promises ♪
♪ 맹세로 증명하지 않아도 ♪
♪ The dusk when we once vowed to stay together ♪
♪ 함께하자 약속했던 그 황혼은 ♪
♪ No need to cling to forever ♪
♪ 영원을 고집할 필요는 없어 ♪
♪ Allow parting to happen quietly ♪
♪ 이별이 조용히 찾아오게 내버려둬 ♪
♪ The inner voice hidden in the origami ♪
♪ 종이접기에 숨겨 둔 속마음 ♪
♪ Each scratch and line is proof of beauty ♪
♪ 남은 선과 자국 하나하나가 아름다웠던 순간의 증거야 ♪
Your clothes.
옷
Sit up straight.
다들 똑바로 앉아
Come on, let's start from the right.
자, 오른쪽부터 시작하자
First one, Zheng Feiyang.
정페이양부터 말해
Come on.
자, 얼른
Coach, when you first showed up,
코치님이 처음 오셨을 땐
we all thought you were a fraud.
저희 다 코치님이 사기꾼인 줄 알았어요
You pretended to know about football just to hit on Ms. Lin.
선생님한테 잘 보이려고 축구를 아는 척하는 줄 알았죠
But we didn't expect that you weren't pretending.
근데 아는 척이 아니라
You really know football.
진짜 잘 아시더라고요
It really felt like hitting the jackpot.
정말 하늘에서 뚝 떨어진 행운 같았어요
At first, I was wondering
저도 처음에는
why someone so amazing came to teach us.
어떻게 이렇게 대단한 분이 우릴 가르치러 오셨나 싶었죠
We wouldn't even dare dream of such luck before.
예전엔 이런 행운을 상상도 못 했거든요
Yeah.
맞아요
We have to thank you.
그래도 감사합니다
Yes, Coach.
코치님, 진심이에요
Next one.
자, 다음
Let me do it.
내가 할게
Come on.
자, 시작해
Coach.
코치님
I know that you might be
저기... 앞으로
quite busy later on.
많이 바쁘시겠죠?
But it's fine
그래도 가끔
if you come back to guide us occasionally.
돌아와서 저희를 봐 주시면 좋겠어요
Remember to come back.
그리고 꼭 다시 와 주세요
-Remember to come back. -Yes.
- 꼭이요
-Come on, Qi Liang, Qi Liang.
- 자, 치량 차례야
Coach.
코치님
Thank you for making up for many of our regrets.
저희의 많은 아쉬움을 채워 주셔서 감사해요
You...
코치님은
You are like a durian.
꼭 두리안 같아요
Although you look grumpy,
늘 인상을 쓰고 계셨지만
you really taught us a lot.
저희에게 정말 많은 걸 가르쳐 주셨죠
Forever Mr. Winfred.
영원한 윈 선생님이에요
You are amazing.
역시 너라니까
Next one.
다음 사람 말해
Wen Chengye, your turn.
원청예, 말해 봐
Stop pretending.
괜히 폼 잡지 마
Next time we meet,
다음에 뵐 땐
I will become even stronger than before.
지금보다 훨씬 더 강해져 있을게요
Just wait and see.
두고 보세요
As if we won't get stronger.
우리도 강해질 수 있거든?
Boss, your turn.
대장, 네 차례야
-Coach. -Use a handsome gesture.
- 코치님 - 좀 더 멋있게
Okay.
그래, 알았어
Well...
저기...
Coach,
코치님
thank you.
감사합니다
Thank you for going through so much trouble
저희가 이렇게 성장할 수 있게
to train us to this level,
정성껏 가르쳐 주셨잖아요
leading us to defeat Ning'an
코치님 덕분에 닝안을 이기고
and Lyujing.
뤼징도 꺾을 수 있었어요
Thank you and Ms. Lin.
코치님과 린 선생님께 정말 감사드립니다
After you talked with my dad that day,
그날 저희 아빠랑 얘기를 나누신 뒤부터
he changed a lot.
아빠가 완전히 달라진 것 같아요
In my whole life,
지금까지 살면서
the happiest thing is meeting you,
가장 기뻤던 일은 코치님을 만난 거예요
a great coach.
이렇게 좋은 코치님을요
That's enough, okay.
됐어, 이제 그만해
Zhi Hui.
즈후이
Coach.
코치님
I checked your birth chart before.
제가 전에 코치님 사주를 봤는데요
The fortune star is shining on you this year.
올해는 남자 사주에 이성 운이 들어와요
You will meet your true love here
여기서 좋은 인연을 만나
and find real happiness.
진짜 행복을 찾으시나 했는데
I didn't expect you to run away now.
이렇게 떠나실 줄은 몰랐네요
But
그래도
this is also my first mistake.
이번이 처음 틀린 거예요
Don't worry.
걱정 마세요
When you come back next time,
다음에 돌아오시면
I'll read your fortune seriously.
다시 제대로 봐 드릴게요
Then, let's do it next time.
그건 다음에 하고
Chen.
장허
Coach.
코치님
I knew you earlier than they did.
전 다른 애들보다 코치님을 더 먼저 알았어요
You helped Ms. Lin
코치님이 린 선생님 도와
expose that scammer on the field.
경기장 사기꾼을 잡아낸 일도
She told me all about it.
선생님께 전해 들었고요
Actually, before I met you,
사실 코치님을 만나기 전까지
for a long time, I had
전 꽤 오랫동안
lost my passion for football.
축구에 대한 열정을 잃은 채 지냈어요
But after meeting you,
하지만 코치님을 만나고 나서
I realized
깨닫게 됐죠
football is my true love.
제가 진짜 사랑한 건 축구였고
You're just an accident.
코치님은 그저 뜻밖의 계기였다는 걸요
Come on, speak.
자, 네 차례야
Coach.
코치님
During this time,
그동안 저희를
thank you so much for taking care of us.
잘 보살펴 주셔서 정말 감사했습니다
I never thought that
제가 다시 모두와 함께
I could still play football with you all
축구를 할 수 있을 줄은 꿈에도 몰랐어요
and win matches with my brothers.
친구들과 함께 승리를 거둘 줄은 더더욱 몰랐고요
It really felt like
정말 저희 모두
we were in a dream.
꿈을 꾸는 것만 같아요
Thank you, Coach.
감사합니다, 코치님
Next. Fu.
다음, 신수
Fu.
신수
Make it a bit longer.
좀 길게 말해
Captain.
주장
Coach.
코치님
I actually have a lot to say to you.
사실 드리고 싶은 말이 정말 많아요
Do you know the feeling of suddenly having hope?
갑자기 살맛 난다는 게 어떤 기분인지 아세요?
It's like,
이를테면
on a pitch-black road,
온통 칠흑같이 어두운 길에서
I was just spinning in circles
전 계속 제자리만 맴도는 기분이었어요
and couldn't see anything clearly.
아무것도 보이지 않았죠
But you suddenly appeared
그런데 갑자기 코치님이 나타나셨어요
like a beacon.
어둠을 밝히는 등불처럼요
Then, I knew
그 순간 전
I had to go towards you.
코치님이 계신 곳으로 가면 된다는 걸 알았어요
There's actually something I've always wanted to tell you.
사실 코치님께 꼭 드리고 싶었던 말이 있어요
One day,
언젠가는
I will make us your pride.
저희가 코치님의 자랑이 되어 드릴게요
That's too cheesy.
너무 오글거린다
Lu. Lu.
린루, 린루
Next.
네가 다음 차례야
My turn.
내가 찍을게
I thought you wanted to cry.
우는 줄 알았잖아
Coach, you're leaving.
코치님이 떠나신다니
We really can't bear to see you go.
정말 아쉬워요
But we will definitely play well.
하지만 저희는 앞으로도 열심히 뛸게요
Next time we'll show you how good we are.
다음엔 저희가 얼마나 대단한지 보여 드릴 거예요
He's so nervous that he can't even speak clearly.
긴장해서 말도 제대로 못 하네
We also got you a gift,
저희가 선물도 하나 준비했는데
but it's a bit ugly.
예쁘지는 않아요
[Chen Jianghe] [Zheng Ren] [Feng Suo]
[천장허, 정런, 펑쒀]
Ta-da!
짠!
[Zhi Hui] [Qin Ao] [Fu Xinshu]
[즈후이, 친아오, 푸신수]
These are our signatures.
저희 사인이에요
[Yu Ming] [Qi Liang] [Wen Chengye]
[위밍, 치량, 원청예]
[Zheng Feiyang] [Lin Lu]
[정페이양, 린루]
Coach?
코치님이라면
Are you the kind that teaches kids to play football?
유소년 애들 축구 가르치는 그런 코치님이세요?
Coach, we have something for you.
코치님, 드릴 게 있어요
If I force professional tactics on you now,
지금 너희한테 억지로 프로 전술을 가르치면
you will fall.
오히려 감당 못 해
-No.
아니에요
Coach, we can do this.
코치님, 저희 할 수 있어요
-Yes, Coach. -We can do it.
- 맞아요, 코치님 - 할 수 있어요
Do you want to go to Yongchuan Hengjiu?
융촨 헝주로 가고 싶으세요?
If so,
가고 싶다면
just give it to us straight, okay?
시원하게 말씀해 주세요
Without you,
두 분이 안 계셔도
we'll continue to play football.
저희는 축구를 계속할 거예요
Even without you,
두 분이 안 계시더라도
we still have ourselves.
우리에겐 서로가 있잖아
Then let's keep playing football
축구 계속하는 거다
and win the championship together.
다 같이 우승하자
-Kick!
- 축구해야지
Kick to the end.
끝까지 뛰는 거야
and win the championship.
우승하자
Come on.
자, 이리 와
Coach,
코치님
we love you!
- 사랑해요
You are really smart.
참 영리하네요
You know that in the face of money,
사람은 돈 앞에서
people easily lose the courage to speak up.
가장 쉽게 말할 용기를 잃는다는 걸 알고
You chose the best way to shut us up
더는 붙잡지 못하게 입을 막아버릴
and stop us from holding you back.
최고의 방법을 골랐잖아요
You are not the new coach of Yongchuan Hengjiu Club at all.
융촨 헝주의 새 감독은 당신이 아니더군요
You are leaving,
떠난다는 게
not to leave us,
우리가 아니라
but to leave the pitch,
아예 그라운드를 떠나겠다는 거죠?
right?
맞아요?
Let's have a talk.
우리 얘기 좀 해요
I am indeed leaving the pitch.
난 정말 그라운드를 떠날 거예요
Why?
왜요?
Wang Fa.
왕파
I know you are very determined
결심이 확고하다는 것도 알고
and cutting off all possibilities of
마음을 바꿀 여지조차
changing your mind.
남기지 않았다는 것도 알아요
I just want to know
난 그저 진짜 이유가 뭔지
your real reason.
알고 싶을 뿐이에요
Because I don't deserve it.
그럴 자격 없으니까요
I don't deserve to stay here.
난 여기 있을 자격이 없어요
Is it because of
혹시
that little boy who gave up playing football?
축구를 포기한 그 아이 때문인가요?
He never gave up playing football.
그 애는 축구를 포기한 적 없어요
On the contrary, he gave up everything,
오히려 축구를 위해 모든 걸 포기했죠
including himself, to play football.
자기 자신마저도요
He jumped
그 아이는 옥상에서...
off the roof.
옥상에서 뛰어내렸어요
He fell right in front of me.
바로 내 눈앞으로 추락했죠
[Jason]
[제이슨]
[Voice call invitation from Jason]
[제이슨, 음성 통화 요청]
Hello.
여보세요
Jason, where are you?
제이슨, 너 어디야?
I'll arrive at the club soon.
곧 클럽에 도착하니까
Wait for me for a few minutes.
몇 분만 기다려 줘
Jason.
제이슨!
Wang Fa.
왕파
I entrusted my child to you.
내 아이를 당신에게 맡겼는데
Did you really take good care of him?
제대로 돌봐 준 거 맞아요?
The last call he made before he passed away
그 애가 세상을 떠나기 전 마지막으로 건 전화도
was to me.
나한테 한 거였어요
But I couldn't save him.
하지만 난 그 애를 구하지 못했죠
So I swore to find out
그래서 그 애에게 금지 약물을 건넨 사람이
who gave him the banned drugs.
누구인지 반드시 밝혀내겠다고 맹세했어요
I put all the blame on others
모든 책임을 남의 탓으로 돌려
to ease my own guilt.
내 죄책감을 덜어 보려 했던 겁니다
Ridiculous, right?
우습죠?
What about the police?
그럼 경찰은요?
Didn't they help investigate?
경찰은 수사하지 않았나요?
His mother didn't want to cause him secondary harm.
그 애 어머니께서 더는 상처를 남기고 싶지 않다고 하셔서
No autopsy was done.
부검은 하지 않았고
It was ruled a suicide.
결국 자살로 결론 났어요
Even so,
그렇다고 해도
it's not your fault.
그게 당신 잘못이 아니잖아요
You can't give up on your life
그 애 때문에
just because of him.
당신 인생을 포기해선 안 돼요
This is his diary his mother gave me.
이건 그 애 어머니께서 주신 일기장이에요
After reading it, I don't think so.
이걸 읽고 나니 더는 그렇게 생각할 수 없더군요
[During the training in the park today, some high school students]
[오늘 공원에서 추가 훈련하는데 고등학생들이]
[provoked me by saying I am bad at playing soccer and asked me to get lost.]
[시비를 걸더니 축구도 못하면서 꺼지라고 했다]
[One day, I'll prove myself with my skills.]
[언젠가 실력으로 증명하면 더 당당해질 수 있겠지]
He was a very serious and ambitious boy.
그 애는 아주 성실하고 승부욕이 강한 아이였어요
[Mr. Wang is great. I want to prove myself with my skills like him.]
[멋있는 코치님, 나도 코치님처럼 실력으로 인정받고 싶어]
[I haven't written my diary for two months. I don't have enough time.]
[두 달이나 일기를 못 썼다 시간도 없고 스트레스도 심해]
[I'm under a lot of pressure. I got food poisoning last week.]
[지난주에는 배탈이 나서]
He was very strict with himself.
스스로에게도 누구보다 엄격했고요
[I took two days off. During this week's training,]
[이틀간 쉬었다 이번 주에 훈련하는데]
[everyone seems to be better except me. I can't fall behind.]
[나 빼고 다들 달라진 듯했다 절대 뒤처질 수 없어]
So I took his behavior
그래서 나도
[Another teammate left today. Coach didn't say much about it.]
[오늘 또 팀원 한 명이 떠났지만 코치님은 별말이 없었다]
for granted.
그게 당연한 줄만 알았어요
[I know he was eliminated by the club.]
[그 애가 클럽에서 퇴출당했다는 걸 안다]
[The manager said that competition is a purifier.]
[단장님이 경쟁은 옥석을 가리는 일이라고 했다]
[But I felt tired when answering Mom's video call.]
[그래도 엄마와 영상 통화를 하는 건 여전히 힘들다]
He rarely confided his own things to me,
그 애는 자기 얘기를 좀처럼 털어놓지 않았고
[She mumbled a lot and just wanted me to get a good result.]
[엄마는 계속 축구로 성공하라고만 한다]
[I can't let my family look down on me. I want to win, too.]
[가족에게 무시당하지 말라는데 내가 그걸 모르나?]
and I never thought about trying to understand him more.
나도 그 애를 더 알려고 하지 않았어요
Coach said I was not in good condition today.
오늘 코치님이 컨디션이 안 좋아 보인다면서
So I took
그래서 난
-his silence as his prudence. -He asked me if I had enough sleep
- 과묵함을 신중함이라 여겼죠 - 잠은 잘 자고 있는지
and if I was uncomfortable.
어디 아픈 데는 없는지 물으셨다
But that wasn't the case.
하지만 그게 아니었어요
[How could prohibited ingredients be detected]
[내 혈액에서 그게 검출될 리가 없는데]
I didn't dare to tell the truth.
근데 사실대로 말할 엄두가 나지 않았다
[from my blood? I've never used it.]
[금지 성분이라니 난 그런 거 한 적 없어]
He was just a child who needed
그 애는 그저 관심과 위로
[Did I eat anything wrong?]
[혹시 뭘 잘못 먹었나?]
care, comfort, and attention.
보살핌이 필요한 아이였을 뿐이죠
I was expelled.
난 제명당했다
-I only put pressure on him -Why didn't Mr. Wang trust me?
- 나 그 애에게 부담과 - 왜 코치님도 날 안 믿지?
[Why don't you trust me?]
[왜 날 안 믿지?]
-brought him pain. -Why don't you trust me?
- 고통만 안겨 줬어요 - 왜 날 안 믿는 거야?
I know he trusted me
그 애가 자기 자신보다도
[Why don't you trust me? Why don't you trust me?]
[왜 날 안 믿지? 왜 안 믿는 거야?]
even more than he trusted himself.
나를 더 믿었다는 걸 알아요
[Why don't you trust me?]
[왜 날 안 믿지?]
Before he jumped off the roof,
옥상에서 뛰어내리기 전까지
he must have struggled a lot.
분명 한참을 괴로워했겠죠
When everyone didn't trust him,
모두가 그 애를 믿지 않을 때
I was the one who should have trusted him the most,
가장 믿어 줬어야 할 사람이 바로 나였는데
but I didn't.
난 그러지 못하고
I actually doubted him.
오히려 그 애를 의심했어요
He saw me as a beacon,
그 애는 날 등대로 여겼는데
but I didn't light him up.
난 그 애를 비춰 주지 못한 거죠
His mother was right.
그 애 어머니 말씀이 맞아요
I killed Jason.
제이슨은 내가 죽인 거예요
How did Jason
제이슨은
become like this step by step?
어쩌다 그렇게까지 된 걸까요?
Shouldn't football itself
축구는 원래
bring joy and hope?
기쁨과 희망을 안겨 주는 스포츠 아닌가요?
I spent more than half of my life
내 인생 절반 이상을
on football.
축구에 쏟아부었어요
But it wasn't until I was thirty
그런데 서른이 되어서야
that I realized in our industry,
이 업계에서는
effort and time
노력과 시간이
are the least valuable.
가장 가치 없게 여겨진다는 걸 깨달았죠
Out of a hundred players who enter Nanton,
사우샘프턴에 입단한 선수 100명 중
maybe only one will remain at last.
마지막까지 남는 선수는 많아야 한 명이에요
In this process,
그 과정에서
I have to constantly and very quickly
난 끊임없이, 아주 빠르게
abandon any player who can't keep up.
뒤처지는 선수를 포기해야 했죠
Under this high-pressure system of
가치가 없으면
eliminating the worthless,
가차 없이 솎아 내는 고압적인 시스템에선
no one can bear it,
누구라도 버티기 힘들어요
Let alone a proud,
하물며 그 애는 자존심도 강하고
and sensitive young man.
예민한 소년이었잖아요
I often feel that
난 종종
under the banner of the club,
클럽의 깃발 아래 모인
we are like warriors
우리가 마치
united under a primitive totem.
원시 토템 아래 뭉친 전사들 같다고 느꼈어요
It's just a different way.
그저 방식만 달라졌을 뿐이죠
For money
돈을 위해
and victory,
승리를 위해
we fight the opponent.
상대와 치열하게 싸우는 거예요
Are you questioning yourself?
자신을 의심하고 있군요
Yes.
맞아요
I am questioning myself.
난 나 자신을 의심해요
To be faster, higher, and stronger,
더 높이, 더 빠르게 더 강하게
for self-improvement,
자신을 뛰어넘기 위해
for transcending human limits,
인간의 한계를 초월하기 위해
and for these interests,
그런 목표만 좇다 보니
I ignored my players
내 선수들을 돌보지 못했어요
and made them victims
선수들을
in the Colosseum.
투기장의 희생양으로 만든 거죠
I found myself repulsive.
나 자신이 너무 혐오스러워요
Can anyone tell me
누가 좀 알려 줬으면 좋겠네요
what on earth I am doing?
내가 대체 뭘 하고 있는 건지를요
I should go.
이만 가 볼게요
I understand you.
당신을 이해해요
I know that
이 말은
before this,
분명 전에도
many people must have said this to you.
많이 들었을 거예요
But I still want to tell you that
그래도 이 말은 꼭 하고 싶어요
I understand how you feel.
당신이 어떤 심정인지 이해해요
To be honest,
사실
on my way to find you,
당신을 만나러 오면서
I thought of many conversation skills.
어떻게 말해야 할지 계속 고민했어요
But now I find that
하지만 지금 보니
in the face of real problems,
막상 현실 앞에서는
everything seems so barren.
그런 고민도 다 부질없네요
You can laugh at me.
창피한 얘기지만
About a year ago,
1년 전쯤
I was really in a bad state.
난 정말 엉망이었어요
I also reached a very high place.
나도 아주 높은 곳까지 올라갔었죠
Heads,
앞면이 나오면
I go ahead.
앞으로 걸어가는 거고
Tails,
뒷면이 나오면
I stay.
그대로 있는 거야
At that time, I thought that
그때는 정말
life was really meaningless.
인생이 허무하게만 느껴졌어요
In the future, whether it's good
그 뒤로는 좋은 일이든
or bad,
나쁜 일이든
I don't want to experience it anymore.
더는 겪고 싶지 않더군요
You are the same, right?
당신도 그렇죠?
Do you also feel
당신도
that football is meaningless?
축구가 아무 의미 없다고 느껴지나요?
I don't know.
모르겠어요
Here you go.
받아요
A coin toss.
동전 던지기네요
You use a coin to choose sides in soccer.
축구도 동전 던지기로 진영을 결정하잖아요
At that time,
그때 마침
I happened to have a coin in my pocket.
내 주머니에 동전이 하나 있었어요
So I made a decision.
그래서 결심했죠
Heads, I leave.
앞면이 나오면 떠나고
Tails, I stay.
뒷면이 나오면 남기로요
I know I might not be able to convince you.
당신을 설득하기 어렵다는 건 알아요
But I always feel
하지만 왠지
that deep down,
당신 마음속에
you are reluctant to let go.
미련이 남아 있는 것 같네요
Don't ignore
마음속에 남아 있는
that little bit of reluctance left in your heart.
그 작은 미련을 외면하지 말아요
All your emotions
당신의 감정 하나하나가
are precious.
다 소중하니까요
Which side did you
그때는
flip at that time?
어느 쪽이 나왔죠?
Heads.
앞면이요
But you're still here.
그런데도 아직 여기 있네요
Because
내가
I cheated.
꼼수를 썼거든요
♪ Waiting for a dark cloud to pass by you ♪
♪ 먹구름 한 조각이 네 곁을 지나갈 때 ♪
♪ Listen closely to its cries ♪
♪ 그 울음소리에 귀 기울여 봐 ♪
♪ The heavy rain will wash away your reflection ♪
♪ 장대비가 네 그림자를 데려가 ♪
♪ And carry it toward distant scenery ♪
♪ 먼 곳의 풍경을 찾아 떠날 거야 ♪
Ms. Lin.
린 선생님
-Ms. Lin.
- 린 선생님
♪ Every experience has its meaning ♪
♪ 모든 경험에는 저마다의 의미가 있어 ♪
-Get up, Ms. Lin. -Ms. Lin.
- 일어나세요, 린 선생님 - 린 선생님
Are you still sleeping?
잠이 덜 깨신 거 아닐까?
Ms. Lin.
린 선생님
-Ms. Lin.
- 린 선생님
♪ Scene by scene, they come together to form who I am ♪
♪ 장면 하나하나가 모여 지금의 나를 이루지 ♪
Ms. Lin!
린 선생님
Let's go.
가자, 가자
♪ Even the wounds that leave behind their marks ♪
♪ 상처가 흉터로 남는다 해도 ♪
It's so hot.
뜨거워 죽겠네
Take it easy.
조심해, 조심
I only brought a scallion pancake.
난 서우좌빙 하나만 사 왔어
♪ Have taught me how to heal myself ♪
♪ 날 치유하는 법을 배웠어 ♪
I also brought some fruits as I'm afraid other foods are hard to digest.
난 소화 안 될까 봐 과일도 좀 가져왔지
It's early in the morning.
아침부터
Are you preparing a state banquet?
국빈 만찬이라도 준비하는 거야?
♪ The love I gave ♪
♪ 내가 준 사랑은 ♪
Don't you know what day it is today?
오늘이 무슨 날인지 모르시죠?
Today is the third round of Group A in the Champions League.
오늘은 챔피언스 리그 A조 3차전이 있는 날이에요
Watch to learn something.
얼른 보고 좀 배우세요
Come on, Ms. Lin.
오세요, 선생님
Open it.
틀어, 틀어
Come on.
자, 자
-Let's enable screen mirroring. -Come on. Let me enable screen mirroring.
- 화면 연결하자, 화면 - 내가 화면 연결할게
Come on, open it.
자, 얼른 틀어
Okay.
그래, 그래
-Okay. Here we go. Begin. -Come on.
- 됐어, 나온다 - 시작하네
-Here we go. -Nice shot!
- 나왔다 - 나이스
-I can do this kick too.
- 나이스 슛 - 저 정도는 나도 하겠다
Boss, you are overestimating yourself.
대장, 그건 억지야
If you practiced from birth,
태어날 때부터 연습했으면
maybe you could.
가능했을지도 모르지
Let me ask you a question.
얘들아, 뭐 하나만 묻자
Why do you insist on watching the game at my place?
왜 굳이 우리 집에 와서 축구를 보는 거니?
Since Coach left,
코치님이 떠나셨잖아요
Qin Ao was afraid you'd be lonely.
친아오가 선생님 혼자 외로우실까 봐
Then, he called all of us here to keep you company.
저희를 불러 함께 있어 드리자고 했어요
It wasn't me.
아니에요 제가 말한 거 아니에요
It was Fu.
신수가 말했어요
-No.
- 떠넘기네 - 떠넘긴다
We were just afraid you'd be sad alone.
선생님 혼자 힘들어하실까 봐요
Thank you for your concern.
걱정해 줘서 고마워
But don't you guys read the forum?
근데 다들 커뮤니티는 안 봐?
-Forum. -Forum. Forum.
- 커뮤니티요? - 커뮤니티라뇨?
-What forum?
- 무슨 커뮤니티요? - 무슨 커뮤니티지?
-Have a look. -Enable screen mirroring.
- 한번 보자 - 화면으로 연결해
-Coming. -Here.
- 됐다 - 나오네
Insider news.
내부 정보
The head coach of Yongchuan Hengjiu Club is settled,
융촨 헝주 감독 최종 확정
[Breaking news! According to the member of Yongchuan Hengjiu,]
[속보, 융촨 헝주의 내부 관계자에 따르면]
[they want the former vice-director of the training camp of Nanton,]
[전 사우샘프턴 유소년 팀 부책임자였던]
Winfred.
- 윈프레드
[a young coach named Winfred.]
[젊은 코치 윈프레드를 영입할 예정이라고 한다]
Yongchuan Hengjiu Club poached our guy.
융촨 헝주가 우리 코치님을 빼 갔잖아
If I get rich one day,
나중에 내가 돈 많이 벌면
I'll poach Coach back.
코치님을 다시 모셔 올 거야
Scroll down more.
더 밑으로 내려 봐
[Internal information! The head coach of Yongchuan Hengjiu has been selected.]
[내부 정보 융촨 헝주 감독 최종 확정]
[Yongchuan Hengjiu Football Club]
[융촨 헝주 축구 클럽은]
[appoint Liu Chuanguang as the head coach of Team 1]
[류촨광을 1군 감독으로 임명함]
Yongchuan Hengjiu Football Club
융촨 헝주 축구 클럽은
appoints Liu Chuanguang as the head coach of the first team.
류촨광을 1군 감독으로 임명함
Yongchuan Hengjiu Club finally chose Coach Liu.
융촨 헝주가 결국 류 코치를 선택했네
What about our coach?
그럼 우리 코치님은?
He couldn't have gone back to Nanton, right?
사우샘프턴으로 돌아가신 건 아니겠지?
Where did our coach go?
우리 코치님은 어디 가셨죠?
Where is our coach?
우리 코치님은요?
-Who? Who? -Someone is knocking.
- 누구세요? - 누가 문 두드리는데요
-Who?
- 누가 문 두드려요 - 누구세요?
I also ordered takeout.
나도 배달 음식 시켰어
Slide down.
- 아래로 내려 봐 - 더 내려 봐
Don't worry.
좀 기다려
Why?
왜지?
-Is it true? -It should be true.
- 진짜야? - 이건 진짜일 거야
It's official.
공식 발표잖아
Take a look at where the coach went.
코치님이 어디 가셨는지 한번 봐 봐
-Official. -Yes.
- 공식 발표야 - 그래
It's really Liu Chuanguang.
진짜 류촨광이 맞나 봐
What does it mean?
무슨 뜻이지?
-It's Liu Chuanguang. -Why is it Liu Chuanguang?
- 류촨광이 맞아 - 왜 바뀐 거지?
So many food.
아침거리가 엄청 많네
I wouldn't have bought it if I knew.
진작 알았으면 안 사 왔을 거야
Coach!
- 코치님
You haven't left?
정말 안 가셨군요
No. Coach.
- 안 가셨네요 - 코치님
You are...
여기 계셨군요
♪ Your voice is like the wind ♪
♪ 바람을 닮은 네 목소리 ♪
Coach.
코치님
♪ Things will eventually change ♪
♪ 세상이 끝내 변해도 ♪
You're still here
아직 안 가셨군요?
♪ You're still obsessed with me♪
♪ 변함없는 네 의지를 봤어 ♪
Since you don't want me here, I'll go.
다들 내가 온 게 싫은가 본데 그럼 나 간다
♪ Those surging secrets ♪
♪ 남몰래 일렁이던 그 비밀들을 ♪
No, Coach. Sit.
- 아니에요, 코치님 - 앉으세요
♪ You hid in my eyes ♪
♪ 눈빛 깊숙이 감춘 채 ♪
Wait, Coach.
아니, 코치님
Did Yongchuan Hengjiu reject you?
융촨 헝주에서 퇴짜 맞으신 거 아니에요?
♪ I witnessed your persistence ♪
♪ 힘겨운 시간을 견뎌 온 널 봤지 ♪
Weren't you poached?
스카우트되신 거 아니었나요?
♪ The change will come true ♪
♪ 변화는 예정대로 찾아오고 ♪
After careful consideration,
곰곰이 생각해 봤는데
♪ I've seen it clearly ♪
♪ 난 이미 알았어 ♪
I think you brats
역시 너희 말썽꾸러기들이
are much more interesting.
더 재밌겠더라
♪ The situation by your side ♪
♪ 네 곁에서 마주할 운명을 ♪
Who are you calling brats?
- 누가 말썽꾸러기예요? - 말썽꾸러기라뇨
Coach, let me ask you.
코치님, 여쭤볼 게 있는데요
♪ I give up the past ♪
♪ 지난날의 흔적을 버리고 ♪
Why did you suddenly change your mind?
갑자기 왜 마음을 바꾸셨어요?
♪ Our true selves ♪
♪ 우리의 본모습으로 돌아가도 ♪
Yeah.
맞아요
I told you I couldn't bear to leave you guys.
너희가 너무 마음에 걸리더라
♪ I can't persistent any longer ♪
♪ 더는 버텨낼 수가 없어 ♪
♪ High in the sky ♪
♪ 드넓은 하늘 끝에서도 ♪
Coach, could you not bear to leave us
저희를 두고 가기 싫으셨군요
♪ You know how I feel ♪
♪ 넌 내 마음을 알아 ♪
or…
마음에 걸리다니
Could you really not bear to leave us...
정말 저희 때문에 남으신 거예요?
♪ Will I become you ♪
♪ 너를 닮고 싶어도 ♪
Or Ms. Lin?
아니면 린 선생님 때문에 남으신 거예요?
♪ I want to be myself ♪
♪ 나답게 살아갈 거야 ♪
♪ If time can reach ♪
♪ 시간이 허락한다면 ♪
I really couldn't bear to leave her either.
린 선생님도 마음에 걸렸지
♪ I will remove all the deception ♪
♪ 모든 가식을 벗어던지고 ♪
♪ If you follow your heart ♪
♪ 마음이 이끄는 대로 가 ♪
What, do I not deserve it?
왜, 내가 부족하니?
♪ The ending is predestined ♪
♪ 결말은 하늘의 뜻에 맡겨 둬 ♪
Of course you do.
- 그럴 리가요 - 아니죠
-Of course. -You are the best in the world.
- 아니에요 - 세상에서 두 분이 최고예요
♪ The change will come true ♪
♪ 변화는 예정대로 찾아오고 ♪
Thank you, Ms. Lin.
- 린 선생님, 감사합니다
♪ I've seen it clearly ♪
♪ 난 이미 알았어 ♪
Since Coach isn't leaving,
코치님도 남기로 하셨으니
let's have hot pot for lunch to celebrate.
점심때 훠궈 먹으면서 축하하자
♪ The situation by your side ♪
♪ 네 곁에서 마주할 운명을 ♪
Sure. I haven't had hotpot for a long time.
- 좋지 - 훠궈 안 먹은 지 오래됐네
♪ I give up the past ♪
♪ 지난날의 흔적을 버리고 ♪
Since you suggested it, it's your treat.
네가 제안한 거니까 네가 사
Right, your treat.
맞아, 네가 사
♪ Our true selves ♪
♪ 우리의 본모습으로 돌아가도 ♪
The place we saved last time. Let's go there.
지난번에 저장해 둔 그 가게로 가자
At the school gate.
학교 앞에 있는 가게 말이야
♪ I can't persistent any longer ♪
♪ 더는 버텨낼 수가 없어 ♪
How much is it?
얼마나 나오려나?
-No. -Can you afford it, Qin Ao?
- 아니, 이게... - 친아오, 살 돈은 있어?
♪ High in the sky ♪
♪ 드넓은 하늘 끝에서도 ♪
Coach won't leave, so he should treat.
코치님이 남으셨으니 당연히 코치님이 사셔야지
♪ You know how I feel ♪
♪ 넌 내 마음을 알아 ♪
I'll return it to you
주인한테 돌려줄게요
♪ Will I become you ♪
♪ 너를 닮고 싶어도 ♪
Please, Coach. Right?
- 코치님이 사는 거야 - 그렇지?
♪ I want to be myself ♪
♪ 나답게 살아갈 거야 ♪
♪ If time can reach ♪
♪ 시간이 허락한다면 ♪
♪ I will remove all the deception ♪
♪ 모든 가식을 벗어던지고 ♪
♪ If you follow your heart ♪
♪ 마음이 이끄는 대로 가 ♪
It's my treat.
내가 살게, 내가
I'll treat.
내가 사면 돼
♪ The ending is predestined ♪
♪ 결말은 하늘의 뜻에 맡겨 둬 ♪
Who exactly is treating?
대체 둘 중에 누가 사는 거야?
To be honest,
솔직히 말해서
I think the decision you made
네가 지금 한 결정이
is absolutely correct.
전적으로 옳다고 생각해
Don't worry about anything else.
다른 건 다 내려놓고
The most important thing
지금은 네 삶을
is to get your life back on track.
다시 잘 꾸려나가는 게 제일 중요한 거야
I must have told you before.
내가 분명 말했지
When you speak to me like an elder,
네가 윗사람 행세하면서 말할 때마다
you're asking for a beating.
한 대 쥐어박고 싶다고
Is that how you talk to your elder?
윗사람한테 무슨 말버릇이야?
I am your brother-in-law.
내가 매형이니까
That makes me half an elder to you.
반은 윗사람이나 마찬가지지
So...
그럼...
Did you tell Lin Wanxing
모든 일을
everything about the situation?
린완싱한테 털어놓은 거야?
I'm curious, wasn't she angry?
궁금하네, 너한테 화 안 내?
Didn't she push you off the roof?
옥상에서 밀지는 않았어?
Not exactly everything.
전부 말한 건 아니야
Okay, don't say anything. Let me guess.
됐어, 말하지 마 내가 맞혀 볼게
You told her everything
제이슨에 관한 일은
about Jason.
전부 얘기했지만
But you didn't tell her
훙징에 온 목적이
that you came to Hongjing
린 선생을 조사하러 온 거라는 얘긴
to investigate her, right?
쏙 뺐겠네, 맞지?
Bro, listen to me.
친구야, 충고 하나만 할게
If you keep hiding this from her,
그 일을 계속 감추다가는
it will end badly.
나중에 수습하기 더 힘들 거야
Don't I know that?
내가 그걸 모르겠어?
Then what will you do?
그럼 어떻게 할 건데?
You can't hide it forever.
계속 숨길 수도 없잖아
Even if she knew the truth,
린 선생이 진실을 알게 돼도
she wouldn't push me off the roof.
날 옥상에서 밀진 않을 거야
She would just push me away.
대신 날 밀어내겠지
I want that even less.
난 그게 더 싫어
So I can only wait.
그러니까 기다릴 수밖에 없어
I can only explain it to her
모든 진실을 밝혀낸 뒤에야
after I investigate everything clearly.
설명할 자격이 생기니까
Is there any progress in the UK?
영국 쪽은 진전이 있어?
Yes.
있지
Every time his team pulls off
그의 팀이 강팀을 꺾는
such an abnormal upset,
수상쩍은 경기들이 끝날 때마다
Kevin makes a huge expenditure.
케빈은 늘 거액을 지출했어
The luxury cars, yachts, and real estate under his name
케빈 명의로 등록된 고급 승용차와 요트, 부동산도
all exceed his financial capacity.
전부 그의 자산 수준을 훨씬 웃돌았지
Why didn't you mention such important progress earlier?
그렇게 중요한 걸 알아냈는데 아까 왜 말 안 했어?
Are you kidding me?
장난하냐?
I was caring for my junior,
난 그냥 윗사람으로서
and doing what an elder should do.
아랫사람을 챙기는 거라고
So, he...
그러니까
He has the profit
케빈은 이득도 봤고
and the motive.
동기도 충분하네
Now we only lack
이제 케빈과 스페이드 Q의
his connection to Spade Q.
연관성만 밝혀내면 돼
As for the rest,
하지만 다른 부분은
we are still investigating.
아직 캐는 중이야
[A gift for Wang Fa's returning]
[왕파에게, 복귀 선물]
[Superstar Slacker]
[느긋한 초신성]
Thanks, this one looks...
고마워요, 이거 꼭...
It looks a lot like you. Welcome back to the Little Savage Tribe.
당신 닮았죠, 야인 부족에 돌아온 걸 환영해요
[Zhou Hui]
[주간 조회]
Wait a minute.
잠깐만
Go easy on me,
좀 봐줘
Wen Chengye.
원청예 학생
You're on duty today.
오늘 당번은 너구나
Be a good boy.
말썽 피우지 마
Likewise,
선생님 걱정이나 하세요
the Queen of Being Late.
맨날 지각하시면서
It's not time yet, is it?
아직 시간 안 됐잖아
Now it is.
이제 됐네요
Congratulations,
축하합니다
you're late again.
또 지각이군요
Your morality points should be fully deducted by now.
생활 점수도 바닥났겠어요
Likewise.
네 걱정이나 해
Thanks.
고마워요
You really helped me a lot.
정말 큰 도움이 됐어요
Are you a teacher here too?
혹시 우리 학교 선생님이세요?
Li, are you Ju Li?
샤오리? 너 쥐리구나
Good thing you still remember the code.
용케 암호를 기억하고 있었네
Long time no see, Wanxing.
오랜만이야, 완싱
It really is you.
진짜 너였구나
Li, why are you at Hongjing No. 8 High School?
샤오리, 네가 어떻게 우리 학교에 있어?
Today is my first day of work.
오늘이 출근 첫날이야
Work?
출근이라고?
We'll be colleagues from now on.
그럼 우리 이제 동료구나
Deskmates in middle school,
중학교 땐 짝꿍이었는데
now colleagues.
지금은 직장 동료가 됐네
You can't get rid of me in the future.
이제 나한테서 못 벗어날걸?
That's great.
정말 잘됐다
I'm going to a meeting. And you?
난 회의에 가야 하는데 너는?
I'll report to the grade group first,
먼저 교무실에 가서 인사드리고
then go to class.
수업 들어가야지
I'll come find you later.
그럼 이따가 찾아갈게
I'm running out of time.
늦겠다
I'll go first.
먼저 가 볼게
Okay.
알았어
Did you guys hear?
그거 들었어?
A new teacher seems to have come to our grade group,
우리 학년에 새 선생님이 오셨대
said to be a physics genius
물리 천재라고 하더라
who made the national Physics Olympiad Team.
국가 물리 올림피아드 대표 팀 출신이래
She seems to have graduated from an Ivy League university.
아이비리그 졸업생이라던데
Come on.
말도 안 돼
What kind of big genius would come to our dump?
어떤 천재가 이런 후진 학교에 오겠냐?
Even so, bro,
그래도 말이야
we will have the best coach
우리한텐 최고의 코치님과
and the best teacher.
최고의 선생님이 계시잖아
-Yeah. -That's an amazing and cool place.
- 맞아 - 인재가 모이는 명당답게
The amazing Hongjing No. 8 High School emerged from nowhere.
훙징 제8고가 혜성처럼 등장하는 거지
I hope so.
그랬으면 좋겠다
Zhi Hui is telling the fortune again.
즈후이가 또 점을 보네
Why don't you calculate how the Feng Shui is today?
오늘 운세가 어떤지 좀 봐 줘
We'll get scolded by Coach.
코치님한테 혼날 거야
Stop.
그만
What's going on?
왜들 이래?
I've been too gentle with you lately, huh?
요즘 내가 너무 다정하게 대해 줬지?
How is that possible, Coach?
- 아니에요 - 그럴 리가요, 코치님
A misunderstanding of 'gentle'.
다정함의 뜻을 모르시나 봐요
After finishing this,
이거 끝나면
do two more sets of endurance training.
지구력 훈련 2세트 더 해
Coach, our legs are almost dead.
코치님, 다리가 풀릴 지경이에요
Three sets.
3세트
Okay.
네
What a coincidence.
진짜 신기하네
-Go on. -I didn't expect
- 계속해 - 네가 여기서
you to come teach here, too.
가르치게 될 줄은 정말 몰랐어
See those little blue elves?
저기 파란 유니폼 입은 애들 보여?
Come on, next set, get ready.
자, 다음 조 준비!
Let me officially introduce them to you.
정식으로 소개할게
They are members of the football team I lead.
쟤네가 바로 내가 맡은 축구팀이야
And the guy in the knit sweateris
그리고 저기 니트 입은 사람이
their coach,
저 아이들 코치인
Wang Fa. Let's go.
왕파야, 가자
Let me introduce.
소개해 줄게
This is my good friend Ju Li.
내 친구 쥐리예요
She also came to our school to teach.
얘도 우리 학교에서 물리를
She teaches physics.
가르치게 됐어요
Hello, Coach Wang.
안녕하세요, 왕 코치님
I am Ju Li,
쥐리라고 해요
Wanxing's childhood friend.
완싱의 소꿉친구죠
Wang Fa.
왕파예요
By the way, Wanxing,
맞다, 완싱
I need to head back to the team first.
나 먼저 부서에 가 볼게
They want me to give a report.
보고할 게 있거든
Anyway, just don't forget about Saturday.
아무튼 토요일 약속만 잊지 마
Got it. Go ahead.
알았어, 얼른 가
You have plans for Saturday?
토요일에 약속 있어요?
Yeah, Li planned to take me camping
네, 샤오리가 캠핑 가자고 했어요
to get close to nature.
자연 좀 만끽하자고요
Didn't we agree to have roast duck on Saturday?
토요일에 우리 오리구이 먹기로 했잖아요
Yes.
맞다
How about Sunday?
그럼 일요일은 어때요?
But
근데
didn't you promise to take me shopping on Sunday?
일요일엔 나랑 쇼핑하러 가기로 했잖아
I just got here.
나 여기 온 지 얼마 안 됐어
Look at my bad memory.
내 정신 좀 봐
How about we go next week?
그럼 우리 다음 주에 먹으러 가요
A restaurant can be booked anytime, right?
식당 예약은 언제든 할 수 있잖아요
When are you going to have roast duck?
오리구이는 언제 먹으러 가는데요?
I like it, too. Let's go together.
나도 좋아하니까 끼워 줘
Sure. Let's go together.
좋지, 그럼 같이 가자
My treat as an apology.
미안하니까 내가 살게
Great. Then I'll go camping too.
좋아요, 그럼 나도 캠핑에 끼워 줘요
I like camping, too.
나도 캠핑 좋아하거든요
I think camping is more fun with more people.
캠핑은 사람이 많을수록 더 재밌는 것 같아요
Then let's go together with Li.
그럼 샤오리, 다 같이 가자
Sure. If you're okay,
그래, 너만 괜찮다면
I'm fine with it.
나도 괜찮아
I'll get back to work.
먼저 가 볼게요
Three more sets of training.
3세트 더 하자
Don't be like this.
그러지 마
Wanxing.
완싱
-Is that heavy? Let me help you. -Here.
- 그거 무거워? 도와줄게 - 이리 줘요
Thank you.
고마워요
You guys are so nice.
다들 너무 친절하네
Felix Yu said he's almost here.
위보가 거의 다 왔대요
They're here.
저기 오네요
Why are you here?
여긴 웬일이야?
Miss Celeste?
하늘 씨
My name is Wang Tian.
난 왕톈이라고 해요
Ms. Lin.
린 선생님
We meet again.
또 뵙네요
♪ There's nothing to fear ♪
♪ 두려울 게 없어 ♪
♪ Because you're with me ♪
♪ 네가 있으니까 ♪
♪ The light shimmers ♪
♪ 희미한 빛이 비쳐 ♪